<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tools | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/categories/tools/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-28T21:52:25+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Support Details - tech support management]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2010/04/22/support-details-tech-support-management/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-22T16:52:47+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2010/04/22/support-details-tech-support-management</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever dealt with a client where you wanted to know their operating environment? Thinks like what operating system they are running (and version), which browser type and version, whether they have JavaScript enabled etc? Sounds easy but for some clients this is like being asked to provide a detailed analysis of early 7th century rock formations around Stone Henge...in Latin. :(</p>

<p>Here's a super simple solution that anyone could use :)</p>

<p><a href="http://supportdetails.com/">http://supportdetails.com/</a></p>

<p>Basically you send your client the URL above which they open. The web page will automatically detect their environment, all they have to do is enter your email address in a text box and click a button and in seconds you'll receive an email detailing the system they are using. Nice!</p>

<p>If you want to make it even easier you can provide the URL to them with your email already attached:</p>

<p>E.g. http://supportdetails.com/?recipient=developer@mycompany.com</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BrowserLab live on adobe.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2009/10/30/browserlab-live-on-adobe-com/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-30T12:02:27+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2009/10/30/browserlab-live-on-adobe-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm probably a bit behind the times with this one, but Adobe have added "BrowserLab" functionality to "<em>preview and test your web pages on leading browsers and operating systems - on demand</em>".</p>

<p>Seems to work like other paid services, but is free :)</p>

<p><a href="https://browserlab.adobe.com/">https://browserlab.adobe.com/</a></p>

<p>Available browser options (across mac and windows) include:</p>

<ul>
<li>IE 6/7/8</li>
<li>Firefox 2/3</li>
<li>Safari 3/4</li>
</ul>


<p><a href="http://www.chapter31.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/Screen-shot-2009-10-30-at-11.58.48-AM.png"><img src="http://www.chapter31.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/10/Screen-shot-2009-10-30-at-11.58.48-AM-300x166.png" alt="michaelsharman.com" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google releases video chat]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/11/12/google-releases-video-chat/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-12T14:04:21+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/11/12/google-releases-video-chat</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For those that use gtalk/gmail, google have finally caught up and released <a href="http://mail.google.com/videochat">voice and video chat</a>.</p>

<p>They even help you <a href="http://www.google.com/mail/help/videochat/learnmore.html">buy a webcam</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aqua Data Studio 7 includes an ER modeler]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/10/22/aqua-data-studio-7-includes-an-er-modeler/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-22T14:23:49+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/10/22/aqua-data-studio-7-includes-an-er-modeler</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Those of you who miss diagramming support when using MySQL tools will be pleased to know that the <a href="http://www.aquafold.com/d7/docs/index.html">latest version</a> of <a href="http://www.aquafold.com/">Aqua Data Studio</a> has support for ER Modeling :)</p>

<blockquote><p>The Entity-Relationship (ER) Modeler we’ve built into Aqua Data Studio 7 is as powerful as even the best standalone database diagramming tools. Use it to design a new database from scratch, understand and clean up a database nightmare in your office, or visually understand entity relationships in existing databases to write more effective SQL queries. Then share your diagram with the team through Aqua Data Studio’s integrated Subversion (SVN) and CVS source control clients.</p></blockquote>

<p>I've really missed creating Entity Relationship diagrams when using MySQL as they are fantastic during planning and of course offer great documentation for all developers, particularly as your project (and database) grows.</p>

<p>This will start filling a huge hole and help to close the gap in comparison to other vendors database tools.</p>

<p>ADS is a comercial product so hopefully diagramming will be added to the free MySQL Administrator soon.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.chapter31.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/adsmodeler.jpg"><img src="http://www.chapter31.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/adsmodeler-300x225.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[mooFlair on Adobe's top 10 list]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/09/04/mooflair-on-adobes-top-10-list/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-04T08:33:59+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/09/04/mooflair-on-adobes-top-10-list</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Areez Gangji has just posted on <a href="http://www.adobe.com/devnet/">Adobe devnet</a> an article listing the "<a href="http://www.adobe.com/devnet/flex/articles/apps_students.html">Top 10 Adobe Flex and AIR applications for students</a>".</p>

<p>I'm very proud to say that a good friend (and fellow <a href="http://www.daemon.com.au/">Daemon</a> alumni) <a href="http://mxbase.blogspot.com/">Patrick Tai</a> has an app on their called <a href="http://mooflair.com/">mooFlair</a> which he originally built for the AIR derby.</p>

<p>What is mooFlair?</p>

<blockquote><p>A desktop application that helps you to manage and watch both online and offline FLVs videos. More than a simple flv player, build your own FLV library and save your compilations in playlists.
Import FLVs from your computer - including h.264 encoded videos, browse categorised RSS Feeds or search directly from the most popular video content providers and add new video clips to your searchable library. If you need to watch all your videos off line, simply use the download option.</p></blockquote>

<p>Rss feeds and search are available for the following content providers:</p>

<ul>
<li>YouTube</li>
<li>BlipTv</li>
<li>Dailymotion</li>
<li>Metacafe</li>
<li>5min Life Videopedia</li>
<li>SpikedHumour</li>
</ul>


<p>I've been using mooFlair for a while now and it's fantastic. Check it out, there's even an <a href="http://mooflair.com/demo/index.html">online demo</a> to try :)</p>

<p><a href="http://mooflair.com/"><img src="http://www.chapter31.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/09/screenshotnew.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
