<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: AIR | chapter31 &raquo;]]></title>
  <link href="http://chapter31.com/categories/air/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chapter31.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-06T22:59:39+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://chapter31.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Sharman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[mooFlair on Adobe's top 10 list]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2008/09/04/mooflair-on-adobes-top-10-list/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-04T08:33:59+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2008/09/04/mooflair-on-adobes-top-10-list</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Areez Gangji has just posted on <a href="http://www.adobe.com/devnet/">Adobe devnet</a> an article listing the "<a href="http://www.adobe.com/devnet/flex/articles/apps_students.html">Top 10 Adobe Flex and AIR applications for students</a>".</p>

<p>I'm very proud to say that a good friend (and fellow <a href="http://www.daemon.com.au/">Daemon</a> alumni) <a href="http://mxbase.blogspot.com/">Patrick Tai</a> has an app on their called <a href="http://mooflair.com/">mooFlair</a> which he originally built for the AIR derby.</p>

<p>What is mooFlair?</p>

<blockquote><p>A desktop application that helps you to manage and watch both online and offline FLVs videos. More than a simple flv player, build your own FLV library and save your compilations in playlists.
Import FLVs from your computer - including h.264 encoded videos, browse categorised RSS Feeds or search directly from the most popular video content providers and add new video clips to your searchable library. If you need to watch all your videos off line, simply use the download option.</p></blockquote>

<p>Rss feeds and search are available for the following content providers:</p>

<ul>
<li>YouTube</li>
<li>BlipTv</li>
<li>Dailymotion</li>
<li>Metacafe</li>
<li>5min Life Videopedia</li>
<li>SpikedHumour</li>
</ul>


<p>I've been using mooFlair for a while now and it's fantastic. Check it out, there's even an <a href="http://mooflair.com/demo/index.html">online demo</a> to try :)</p>

<p><a href="http://mooflair.com/"><img src="/images/uploads/2008/09/screenshotnew.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[cfdocs on air (livedocs for CF8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2008/02/22/cfdocs-on-air-livedocs-for-cf8/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-22T09:33:59+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/22/cfdocs-on-air-livedocs-for-cf8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://brianflove.com/">Brian Love</a> recently <a href="http://blog.brianflove.com/articles/2008/02/19/cfdocs-on-air">released an AIR application</a> he wrote which wraps up the <a href="http://livedocs.adobe.com/coldfusion/8/htmldocs/index.html">ColdFusion 8 'livedocs'</a>.</p>

<p>This is a great idea and a fantastic tool to add to your list. I'm sure most developers use livedocs as a reference (I do all the time) but historically the are SO slow (not to mention that I think Adobe needs to invest in a little SEO as I often get CF6 livedocs at the top of Google results!).</p>

<p>The CF8 online docs were given a much needed face lift but still are a little slow and the initial page always reloads into a frameset.</p>

<p>While we do have tools like <a href="http://www.cfquickdocs.com/">cfquickdocs</a> which are great, having everything as a local resource on your file system makes life a lot easier :)</p>

<p>Now I just need to wait until Adobe releases AIR for Linux so I can use this at work :(</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google analytics AIR app]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2007/09/25/google-analytics-air-app/"/>
    <updated>2007-09-25T12:26:32+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2007/09/25/google-analytics-air-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An interesting AIR app has been <a href="http://www.aboutnico.be/index.php/google-analytics-air-beta-sign-up/">released in Beta</a> for <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics">Google analytics</a>.</p>

<p>From the author:</p>

<blockquote><p>The Google Analytics Reporting suite is an Adobe AIR application that brings Google Analytics to the desktop. It uses it’s own custom API to interact with Google and nearly implements all features of Analytics.</p></blockquote>

<p>You can even export the data to PDF, XLS (Excel) and XML.</p>

<p>Nice :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
