<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cfeclipse | chapter31 &raquo;]]></title>
  <link href="http://chapter31.com/categories/cfeclipse/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chapter31.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-03T12:11:20+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://chapter31.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Sharman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development configuration tips for Ubuntu]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2008/12/13/development-configuration-tips-for-ubuntu/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-13T13:28:20+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2008/12/13/development-configuration-tips-for-ubuntu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just setup my machine at home with Ubuntu 8.10 (desktop) which was so easy think I saved hours off the time it would normally take with Windows. So much is already installed and ready to go and with apt (or the Synaptic package manager) it's super quick to download and install extra things things like MySQL, PHP, Apache, Java etc</p>

<p>Here are some notes which helped me out when configuring some of these development tools.</p>

<p>This assumes you've already installed Apache and MySQL, for notes on installing these I <a href="http://ubuntuexperiment.wordpress.com/2008/11/10/installing-apache-php-mysql/">found this article</a> to be a great resource.</p>

<p>If you get this message when you restart Apache, "<em>Could not reliably determine the server’s fully qualified domain name, using 127.0.1.1 for ServerName</em>", edit /etc/apache2/conf.d/fqdn and add "ServerName localhost":</p>

<p><code>
sudo nano /etc/apache2/conf.d/fqdn
</code></p>

<p><strong>Load the mod_rewrite module for Apache</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo a2enmod rewrite
</code></p>

<p><strong>Enable your Apache vhosts</strong></p>

<p>I already had all my vhosts defined in separate <em>.conf</em> files on my windows box, so I copied them all into /etc/apache2/sites-available and setup symbolic links from my /etc/apache2/sites-enabled:</p>

<p><code>
sudo ln -s /etc/apache2/sites-available/mysite.conf /etc/apache2/sites-enabled/mysite.conf
</code></p>

<p><strong>Download and install PHP</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install php5 libapache2-mod-php5
</code></p>

<p><strong>PHP connector to MySQL</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install libapache2-mod-auth-mysql php5-mysql
</code></p>

<p><strong>Install MySQL Administrator</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install mysql-admin
</code></p>

<p><strong>Install subversion</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install subversion
</code></p>

<p>I am also using <a href="http://www.poweredbypulse.com/">Pulse</a> to manage my <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/">eclipse</a> development environment so I needed Java which I got from the Synaptic Package Manager (<em>sun-java6-bin</em>). Pulse is super cool, I used the standard cfeclipse profile with the addition of the PHP PDT (for developing in PHP).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changing the cfeclipse 'tag insight' delay time]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2008/02/28/changing-the-cfeclipse-tag-insight-delay-time/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-28T11:56:02+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2008/02/28/changing-the-cfeclipse-tag-insight-delay-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having 'tag insight' is a great part of any IDE, one which almost every developer takes advantage of irrespective of which editor they use. Tag insight of course being when your IDE provides information (attribute or return information etc) about the tag or function you are currently typing.</p>

<p>Normally when writing a function or tag like <cfhttp>, when you hit the space bar and wait a second a little popup appears detailing exactly what you can do with this tag.</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/2008/02/cfhttp_insight.jpg"><img src="/images/uploads/2008/02/cfhttp_insight.thumbnail.jpg" alt="cfhttp tag insight" /></a></p>

<p>Now this is all lovely except I find that the <em>default time</em> it takes for this to appear (which is 500ms in cfeclipse) is just a little too short for me so that it is more annoying than helpful as it constantly appears when I don't want it to (like after pasting some code it pops up to display all local variables etc).</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/2008/02/taginsight.jpg"><img src="/images/uploads/2008/02/taginsight.thumbnail.jpg" alt="tag insight" /></a></p>

<p>Luckily it's a snap to change these little things :)</p>

<p>Window -> Preferences -> CFEclipse -> Editor</p>

<p><a href="/images/uploads/2008/02/preferences.jpg"><img src="/images/uploads/2008/02/preferences.thumbnail.jpg" alt="cfeclipse preferences" /></a></p>

<p>Then change the <em>Insight Delay</em> value. I now have 1500 which is working nicely.</p>

<p>Don't forget if this is too slow for you (when you actually DO want the tag insight and you find yourself waiting for it) then you can simply hit ctrl + space to launch the tag insight immediately.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Aptana IDE is busted]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2007/08/14/my-aptana-ide-is-busted/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-14T15:45:39+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2007/08/14/my-aptana-ide-is-busted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hmm, running with my past history of having that 'special' touch with computers...my version of Aptana (Aptana IDE (build 0.2.8.15637)) has busted.</p>

<p>Kaput.</p>

<p>Not happy Jan.</p>

<p>I was running an Aptana update yesterday when the network went down. Everything seemed fine until I went to restart Apatana and got the following:</p>

<p><img src="/images/uploads/2007/08/aptana.jpg" alt="Aptana error" /></p>

<p>Damn</p>

<p>Damn</p>

<p>Damn</p>

<p>No fix as yet and roughly 500 lines in the .log file everytime I try to start up telling me I have a hell of a lot of missing bundles :(</p>

<p>Looks like an uninstall/re-install.</p>

<p>I heart computers</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
