<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Apache/IIS | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/categories/apache-slash-iis/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-28T21:54:26+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting font MIME types in apache]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2012/08/10/setting-font-mime-types-in-apache/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-10T09:40:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2012/08/10/setting-font-mime-types-in-apache</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If your website is using custom fonts, you may see this line in your Chrome console:</p>

<blockquote><p>Resource interpreted as Font but transferred with MIME type application/octet-stream</p></blockquote>

<p>This is really kinda annoying, if you want to get rid of that warning then add the following directives to your apache conf/.htaccess:</p>

<p><code>javascript
AddType application/vnd.ms-fontobject eot
AddType font/opentype otf
AddType font/truetype ttf
AddType application/x-font-woff .woff
</code></p>

<p><a href="http://www.jbarker.com/blog/2011/resource-interpreted-font-transferred-mime-type">See here for more information.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache permission denied on Mac OSX Lion]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2012/06/06/apache-permission-denied-on-mac-osx-lion/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-06T00:52:49+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2012/06/06/apache-permission-denied-on-mac-osx-lion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've just upgraded to OSX Lion and had some trouble getting Apache to load a vhost. I kept getting a 403 permission denied error, but all my vhosts had the correct permission directives set.</p>

<p>Now by default your webserver document root is located in <em>/Library/WebServer/Documents</em>. I don't really like that for my local machine, I'd rather store web files under my user account. Just tends to make things easier.</p>

<p>However...if you're getting a 403 error, and something like this in your apache error log (/var/log/apache2/error_log):</p>

<pre><code>[Wed Jun 06 00:36:02 2012] [crit] [client 127.0.0.1] (13)Permission denied: /Users/[username]/Documents/.htaccess pcfg_openfile: unable to check htaccess file, ensure it is readable
</code></pre>

<p>Then check your directory permissions. The interesting thing is that I don't have an .htaccess file in my Documents directory. Even adding one did nothing, so I'm not quite sure why Apache was complaining about this.</p>

<p>The answer was simple, I didn't have "group" read or execute permissions on the <em>Documents</em> directory, once I ran a chmod...everything started working ok :)</p>

<pre><code>chmod 755 Documents
</code></pre>

<p>The actual path to my site was <em>/Users/[username]/Documents/workspaces/sitename/htdocs</em>, but still...without the requisite permissions on the <em>Documents</em> folder Apache couldn't access the vhost.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Development configuration tips for Ubuntu]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/12/13/development-configuration-tips-for-ubuntu/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-13T13:28:20+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/12/13/development-configuration-tips-for-ubuntu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just setup my machine at home with Ubuntu 8.10 (desktop) which was so easy think I saved hours off the time it would normally take with Windows. So much is already installed and ready to go and with apt (or the Synaptic package manager) it's super quick to download and install extra things things like MySQL, PHP, Apache, Java etc</p>

<p>Here are some notes which helped me out when configuring some of these development tools.</p>

<p>This assumes you've already installed Apache and MySQL, for notes on installing these I <a href="http://ubuntuexperiment.wordpress.com/2008/11/10/installing-apache-php-mysql/">found this article</a> to be a great resource.</p>

<p>If you get this message when you restart Apache, "<em>Could not reliably determine the server’s fully qualified domain name, using 127.0.1.1 for ServerName</em>", edit /etc/apache2/conf.d/fqdn and add "ServerName localhost":</p>

<p><code>
sudo nano /etc/apache2/conf.d/fqdn
</code></p>

<p><strong>Load the mod_rewrite module for Apache</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo a2enmod rewrite
</code></p>

<p><strong>Enable your Apache vhosts</strong></p>

<p>I already had all my vhosts defined in separate <em>.conf</em> files on my windows box, so I copied them all into /etc/apache2/sites-available and setup symbolic links from my /etc/apache2/sites-enabled:</p>

<p><code>
sudo ln -s /etc/apache2/sites-available/mysite.conf /etc/apache2/sites-enabled/mysite.conf
</code></p>

<p><strong>Download and install PHP</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install php5 libapache2-mod-php5
</code></p>

<p><strong>PHP connector to MySQL</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install libapache2-mod-auth-mysql php5-mysql
</code></p>

<p><strong>Install MySQL Administrator</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install mysql-admin
</code></p>

<p><strong>Install subversion</strong></p>

<p><code>
sudo apt-get install subversion
</code></p>

<p>I am also using <a href="http://www.poweredbypulse.com/">Pulse</a> to manage my <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/">eclipse</a> development environment so I needed Java which I got from the Synaptic Package Manager (<em>sun-java6-bin</em>). Pulse is super cool, I used the standard cfeclipse profile with the addition of the PHP PDT (for developing in PHP).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Careful when sharing code sent from an IM client]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/06/20/careful-when-copying-code-sent-from-an-im-client/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-20T17:28:11+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2008/06/20/careful-when-copying-code-sent-from-an-im-client</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ok this is a warning to all those who get sent commands to use via IM.</p>

<p>Scenario:</p>

<p>I was helping someone setup their Apache config today, so I copied part of my VirtualHost block to them in an IM client. Then I went to their machine, grabbed the code and pasted it into their .conf file. Then Apache wouldn't start/restart.</p>

<p>After spending 10 minutes scratching my head and comparing code and files etc...I removed all carriage returns/whitespace from the code and woo hoo! Apache started happily.</p>

<p>Same thing happened to me last week where I put some SQL in an IM window, when the recipient got grabbed the query it wouldn't run saying there was a parse error. When he removed the whitespace it worked fine.</p>

<p>Moral of the story?</p>

<p>If you are using code sent to you via IM, when you paste it in remove all carriage returns and white space before using it. Then you can re-format it how you want. You just need to make sure there are no sneaky hidden characters in there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apache, are you secure?]]></title>
    <link href="http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2006/07/16/apache-are-you-secure/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-16T15:15:47+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://michaelsharman.github.io/chapter31/blog/2006/07/16/apache-are-you-secure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.petefreitag.com/">Peter Freitag</a> has a great post on <a href="http://www.petefreitag.com/item/505.cfm">'20 ways to secure your Apache Configuration'</a></p>

<p>Seeing as Apache is a rather popular web server, this is invaluable information for any developer particularly those who are involved with configuring production boxes.</p>

<p>Just how popular is Apache? Have a look at Netcrafts <a href="http://news.netcraft.com/archives/web_server_survey.html">Web Server Survey</a> to September 2006.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.chapter31.com/wp-content/uploads/2006/09/overallc.thumbnail.gif" alt="Netcraft web server survey September 2006" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
