<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | chapter31 &raquo;]]></title>
  <link href="http://chapter31.com/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chapter31.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-19T12:10:26+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://chapter31.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Sharman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dashboard Confessional]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2006/09/07/dashboard-confessional/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-07T00:11:35+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/07/dashboard-confessional</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/uploads/2006/09/6f6eeb2d165f4c7eae2ecfa494f3fd57.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Dashboard Confessional" /></p>

<p>Tonight (well last night considering the time at the moment!) I went to see <a href="http://www.dashboardconfessional.com">Dashboard Confessional</a> at the Hordern Pavillion.</p>

<p>Not a bad show, I am a fan but not a huge one. His voice is quite unique and I like a lot of their tunes. A strong band with good vocals all round. I'd go a 6.5 out of 10</p>

<p>It was interesting being there considering my age and the average age of the people around me...I felt old! A lot of youngsters which is great to see, hopefully more and more of the younger crowd keep enjoying and supporting live music.</p>

<p>The fashion was cracking me up, very 80's, lots of green t-shirts and black leg hugging jeans hehe. Ah to be young and funky :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Busy at the moment?]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2006/09/02/busy-at-the-moment/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-02T13:45:14+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/02/busy-at-the-moment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>"Time is the tiny bits of space between one busy moment and the next."</p></blockquote>

<p>A friend wrote this and got me thinking, I don't know about you but I am always SO busy these days. I used to think that I was just having a busy week or a busy month. Nup...that's life :)</p>

<p>It makes you wonder when you'll have time to 'enjoy' life, so much time is spent at work or doing chores or stuck in traffic etc. I rent at the moment and pay a lot to do it. But in my mind it's worth it for my standard of living. I'm just not interested in spending 2 hours a day stuck in traffic or on the train. I'd rather pay more and be closer to work and life than to lose all that time on travel. After all, time is such a precious commodity and there are lots of things I want to do with it.</p>

<p>That being said I don't have a family! If I did I'm sure my values and beliefs on where I lived would dramatically change.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memory lane]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2006/09/01/memory-lane/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-01T23:34:09+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2006/09/01/memory-lane</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/uploads/2006/09/bottom_r2_c2.thumbnail.jpg" alt="Richard Marx" /></p>

<p>So last night we went to see <a href="http://www.richardmarx.com">Richard Marx</a> at the Capitol. Yeah...I know what you're thinking but that's ok, I'm not afraid to say that I'm a fan and have been for a long time!</p>

<p>Yes it's true I like his voice and his songs, but what I really like is his production and studio band. He always uses the cream of the session muso pool including;</p>

<ul>
<li>Michael Thompson</li>
<li>Michael Landau</li>
<li>Bruce Gaitsch</li>
<li>John Moffet</li>
<li>Lee Sklar</li>
<li>Jeff Porcaro</li>
<li>Steve Lukather</li>
</ul>


<p>Phew...that's quite a list! All of those players above (and many more) I LOVE and would travel miles to see at a gig, if they were to come out to Sydney which is unlikely. The great thing about using guys like this is that you get A-grade quality in touch, tone and taste. Truly memorable parts from the guitar/bass to the kit.</p>

<p>Opening the night was local boy <a href="http://www.rickprice.com.au">Rick Price</a> which was fantastic (yeah I'm a fan of his as well!). Rick hasn't been around (commercially) in this country for a while and I've never seen him live. His performance was pretty special, just him and his acoustic guitar. It must be daunting to be in a situation where you're an opening act and it's just you...no loud band to hide behind. I think he really pulled it off, nice one Rick :)</p>

<p>Monsieur Marx' tour was heralded as the 'Greatest Hits' tour, so as to be expected he played pretty much all the songs you'd know from him. Somebody I was with (and I bet a few others) kept saying "<em>I didn't know he did that!</em>" and the end which was satisfying for me to hear.</p>

<p>The band was quite good although (typically) I would have liked a different guitarist. It didn't help that the sound guy buried him in the mix for the first few songs :(</p>

<p>I'd give it a 7 out of 10, I really liked it but it just didn't have that 'special' something to give it an 8 or 9.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A London gift]]></title>
    <link href="http://chapter31.com/2006/08/12/a-londonn-gift/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-12T23:38:36+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://chapter31.com/2006/08/12/a-londonn-gift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.carlorr.com">Carl Orr</a> is in town but only for a few days. Carl is truly a special guitarist and an old teacher of mine. In fact I even did his original wesite waaaay back in the day (please forgive it now!). Carl has been living in London for about 10 years so it was a long time coming considering I used to see him play almost every other week in the mid 90's.</p>

<p>The gig was at the Seymour Centre and was put on my the good fellows at <a href="http://www.sima.org">SIMA</a>. It was the first time I've been there and it's a really nice 'club', I liked it and will be back!</p>

<p>Also I ran into a friend of mine from UNI days which was a nice surprise.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
